### I. Curriculum vitae

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Dr. Tamás János Szidarovszky

Researcher unique identifier: <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=SVRg0xAAAAAJ">https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=SVRg0xAAAAAJ</a>

Nationality: Hungarian Date of birth: 1985.09.06.

Email address: tamas.janos.szidarovszky@ttk.elte.hu, Website: https://tamas821.github.io/

**SCIENTIFIC INDICATORS (as of 2022.09.01)** 

Citations: 1346, H-index: 19, i10-index: 30. Publications in refereed journals: 46. Book chapters: 3.

#### SHORT INTRODUCTION

I am a theoretical chemist with a higher education in both chemistry and physics. During my PhD studies at the Eötvös Loránd University in Budapest, Hungary, I did research in quantum dynamics and theoretical high-resolution molecular rovibrational spectroscopy, which involved method development as well as applications of general interest. As a postdoc, I utilized my knowledge in high-accuracy molecular modeling in the context of strong field science, in the group of Prof. Kaoru Yamanouchi at The University of Tokyo, where I was later hired as an assistant professor. Eventually I decided to give up my tenure position in Tokyo and attempt to establish a scientific career in my home country.

#### **EDUCATION**

2013	PhD in Theoretical Chemistry - <i>Thesis</i> : <u>Rovibrational spectra near dissociation</u>
	ELTE Eötvös Loránd University, Supervisor: Prof. Attila G. Császár

2013 BSc in Physics

ELTE, Supervisor: Dr. Zoltán Kaufmann

2009 MSc in Chemistry

ELTE, Supervisors: Prof. Attila G. Császár, Dr. Gábor Czakó

#### SHORT RESEARCH VISITS

2008	Group of Prof. Arpád Somogyi, <i>University of Arizona</i> , AZ, USA
	Research topic: Determining the products and the kinetic properties of the tholin-water reaction
	using high recolution mass spectrometry

using high resolution mass spectrometry

2006 Group of Prof. Árpád Somogyi, *University of Arizona*, AZ, USA

Research topic: Automatization of mass spectra analysis

### **CURRENT POSITIONS**

2017 – Research associate

Institute of Chemistry, ELTE Eötvös Loránd University

## **PREVIOUS POSITIONS**

2017 – 2022	Research associate MTA-ELTE Complex Chemical Systems Research Group
2016 – 2017	Assistant professor Department of Chemistry, The University of Tokyo - Yamanouchi Laboratory
2014 – 2016	JSPS postdoctoral fellow Department of Chemistry, The University of Tokyo - Yamanouchi Laboratory
2012 – 2014	Research assistant <i>ELTE Institute of Chemistry and MTA-ELTE Complex Chemical Systems Research Group</i>

### **GRANTS AND FELLOWSHIPS**

2020 - 2024	FK20 Grant (NKFIH Young Researcher Excellence Program)
2020, 2022	Bolyai+ Young Researcher Fellowship (New National Excellence Program)
2020 - 2023	Bolyai János Research Fellowship (Hungarian Academy of Sciences)
2017 - 2020	PD17 Fellowship (NKFIH Postdoctoral Excellence Program)
2014 - 2016	JSPS Postdoctoral Fellowship (Japan Society for the Promotion of Science)
2014	Erdős Pál Young Researcher Fellowship (National Excellence Program)
2007 - 2008	Scholarship of the Hungarian Republic

### PRIZES AND AWARDS

2020	Academic Youth Prize (Hungarian Academy of Sciences)
2019	Michael Polányi Award, youth category (Hungarian Academy of Sciences)
2019	'Excellent researcher of the Institute' (Institute of Chemistry, ELTE)

# 2007 'Excellent student of the Faculty' (Faculty of Sciences, ELTE)

## SUPERVISION OF STUDENTS

2021 – 2022	Tamás Emri (BSc) Institute of Chemistry, ELTE
2019 – 2022	Irén Simkó (MSc and PhD) Institute of Chemistry, ELTE (co-supervisor: Prof. Attila G. Császár)
2016 – 2017	Maho Jono (BSc)  Dept. of Chemistry, The University of Tokyo (co-supervisor: Prof. Kaoru Yamanouchi)
2013 – 2017	Dóra Papp (PhD) <i>Institute of Chemistry, ELTE</i> (co-supervisor: Prof. Attila G. Császár)

## **TEACHING ACTIVITIES**

2022	Physical Chemistry I. practice (BSc), ELTE, Hungary
2021 - 2022	Criterion class in Chemistry for biology majors (BSc), ELTE, Hungary
2020	Physical Chemistry Laboratory (BSc), ELTE, Hungary
2017	Advanced quantum chemistry and structural analysis (PhD level), ELTE, Hungary
2016	Laboratory work in physical chemistry (BSc), The University of Tokyo, Japan
2013	Calculations in physical chemistry (BSc), ELTE, Hungary
2010 - 2011	Mathematical methods in chemistry (MSc), ELTE, Hungary

## **ORGANIZATION OF SCIENTIFIC MEETINGS**

2018	International Symposium on Ultrafast Intense Laser Science (ISUILS2018)
	Visegrád, Hungary. Role: Co-Chair, local organizer
2018	Apharmonicity in Modium Sized Molecules and Clusters (AMOC2018)

2018 Anharmonicity in Medium-Sized Molecules and Clusters (AMOC2018) Budapest, Hungary. Role: local organizer

## **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

2018 –	Member, public body of the Hungarian Academy of Sciences (Committee on Physical Chemistry, Section of Chemical Sciences)
2018 –	Reviewer for the National Research, Development and Innovation Office, Hungary
2020 –	Member, Reviewer Board (Photonics, MDPI)
2021 –	Reviewer for the American Physical Society (APS)
2021 –	Secretary, AMMB Working Committee of the Hungarian Academy of Sciences
2022 –	Review Editor, Phys. Chem. and Chem. Phys. (Frontiers in Chemistry and Frontiers in Physics)